Minu Alex

- minukalex@gmail.com
- J +917306812285
- Pala, Kerala, India
- in linkedin.com/in/minu-alex

OBJECTIVE

10 years experience as Senior Software Engineer. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including HTML5, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, React.js, Redux, Angular, Node.js, Express.js, PHP, JavaScript, Typescript, AJAX, CSS, MySQL and Strong background in project management customer and relations.

SKILLS

Web Technologies: React, Vue.js Angular,, Redux, Node Js,HTML5, CSS3,Ajax, JavaScript, ES6, jQuery, RxJS,XML, JSON, TypeScript

Back End Technologies: PHP, Laravel, Yii, Rest API, Node.js, Next.js

Database: MySql, Mongodb

IDE:VisualStudio Code, Eclipse IDE, IntelliJ

Automation and Testing Tools: Cucumber Js, Jest, Postman

Performance Improvement and Analytics Tools: Jenkins, JIRA, Trello

Cloud: Azure, AWS

CI/CD: Jenkins, Github, GitLab CI,Azure DevOps

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full stack Developer

Bigwater consultancy

March 2022 - March 2024 | Brussels, Belgium

- Technologies Used: React, Redux, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, JSON, XML.Node.js,Next.js,MySql
- Development Environment: Agile/Scrum, Githhub, Azure Devops with frequent requirement changes and active participation in scrum meetings and reviews.
- Real-Time Data Integration: Leveraged RxJS Observables to handle real-time data streams, API endpoints, and WebSocket connections.
- Data Visualization: Utilized backend node.js data binding and rendering capabilities with charting libraries (ngx-charts, Chart.js) to create interactive and visually appealing visualizations (line charts, bar graphs, pie charts, heatmaps).
- User Interactivity: Improved user engagement through interactive controls (dropdown menus, sliders, date pickers, search bars) for filtering, drilling down, and customizing data displays.

Senior Software Engineer

IBS Software

April 2019 - November 2021 | Cochin, India

- Technologies Used: Web Technologies: React.js, Vue.js,
 JavaScript, TypeScript, RxJS, JSON, XML, Bootstrap, HTML5,
 GraphQL, Back End Technologies: PHP, Rest API, Java, Database:
 MySQL, Automation and Testing Tools: Cucumber Js, Jest,
 Postman, Version Control Tools: Git, Jenkins, JIRA, Trello
- **Development Environment:** Worked in an Agile/Scrum environment with frequent requirement changes. Actively participated in scrum meetings and reviews. Maintained and updated work progress in JIRA.
- Real-Time Data Integration: Utilized Angular's Eventemitter and RxJS Subject for efficient communication between components.. Developed multi-module applications with AngularJS and Web Components for modular and reusable UI elements.
- Data Visualization: Created interactive data visualizations using Angular's data binding and rendering capabilities
- User Interactivity: Enhanced user engagement with interactive controls like dropdown menus, sliders, date pickers, and search bars.Implemented responsive and adaptive design techniques for seamless user experiences across devices.
 Worked with web security principles, including OAuth and OpenID Connect, to ensure data integrity and confidentiality.
 Optimized components for maximum performance across various devices and browsers.

TRAINING

PHP Software Training from Spectrum Software Solutions- 07/2013 to 10/2013 Java software Developer Training from Biztime - 03/2014- 07/2014

EDUCATION

B. Tech* (Electronics and Communication Engineering) from St. Joseph's college of Engineering and Technology Pala

M. G University

- ## June 2009 Junel 2013
- Kottayam, India

PROJECTS

HRTAXONE

Custom application developed from scratch for the financial enterprise software, with integrated solution & features such as: Task & Kanban board, Timesheet, Billing, Invoices, Payment integration (3rd party and SEPA), CMS, Email management, Active Directory Integration for Single sign on, User matrix access modules, Email services integration. Alerts, Notification, Accounting modules, Payment reconciliation etc.

Kasal

Designed and implemented user-friendly web interfaces for Kasal banking applications, enhancing the customer experience and increased user engagement and worked in features such as banking product features, such as real-time transaction tracking, personalized financial dashboards, and secure messaging.

Expedia

Flight Booking Platform - Air Expedia - Expedia UI update using React.js, Node.js, 3ds authentication Feature implementation, Expedia Airmate Changes for multi rule creation to make edits to data in the air Configuration

Fullstack developer

Unitybees

July 2017 - April 2019 | Cochin, India

- Technologies Used: Angular 6, REST web services, PHP (Yii2, Yii 1, Codelgniter), JSON, Bootstrap, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git.
- Single Page Application (SPA) Development: Utilized Angular 6 to develop the Explorocity web application with a scalable, maintainable, and feature-rich SPA architecture.
- Reactive Programming with RxJS: Managed asynchronous data streams using RxJS observables, operators, and subjects.
 Implemented reactive forms with Angular's Form Builder and Form Control APIs, enhancing form validation, data manipulation, and submission handling using RxJS operators..
- User Interface and Experience: Developed responsive designs using Bootstrap. Created dynamic and interactive data visualizations and user interfaces.
- Version Control and Collaboration: Managed code versions and collaborations using Git.

Software Engineer

Blue horizon infotech

November 2015 - June 2017 | Cochin, India

- Developed web application using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap 5, PHP, MYSQL, Codelgniter, Yii, Ajax. Collaborated with developers, product marketing teams, and designers, recommending new code development or reuse of existing systems.
- Utilized GIT for project and version management and used JavaScript to optimize web page performance, reducing bandwidth usage and load time.
- Designed, coded, developed, debugged, and tested system specifications for project conversion and development.

Junior web developer

Webcastle

August 2014 - November 2015 | Cochin, India

- Working as a Junior Web Developer and participating in coding, testing, debugging new applications and websites with the team of designers, developers, and content creators to create digital tools.
- Developing the UI layout and front-end programming for a web application that matched requirements. •
- Working in the agile/scrum development environment with frequently changing requirements and actively participating in scrum meetings and reviews.